Finding Aid for Hoover Rupert papers, 1954-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Hoover Rupert papers
1954-1970
Rupert, Hoover.
852170 Aa 2
Methodist clergyman and author; pastor of the Ann Arbor (Mich.) First United Methodist Church. Drafts and galleys of books and articles, correspondence relating to writings and printed sermons.
1 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dr. Hoover Rupert (donor no. 5263 ) and came to the library in 1972.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Hoover Rupert was senior minister of the First United Methodist Church of Ann Arbor, Michigan. He served from 1959 to June of 1972. While in Ann Arbor, Rupert was active in civic affairs and community leadership. He was a leader in the efforts to secure a Fair Housing Ordinance in Ann Arbor. Rupert was also an author, writing fifteen books and a syndicated magazine column.
The collection is comprised almost entirely of drafts of his writings and other materials relating to publication of his writings. There is also an extensive run of his published sermons.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Authors, American--Michigan.; Clergy--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; First Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); United Methodist Church (U.S.)--Michigan--Ann Arbor.MichiganAnn Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Sermons.
- Writings and miscellaneous
  - Writings
    - "My People are Your People" [preliminary draft], 1968; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - "My People are Your People" [galleys], 1968; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - "What's Good About God" [galleys], 1970 (Box 1)
    - "I Belong to the Church" [correspondence], 1954-1955 (Box 1)
    - "I Belong to the Church" [preliminary draft], 1955 (Box 1)
    - "Enjoy your Teenager" [correspondence], 1962 (Box 1)
    - "Christian Citizenship" [correspondence and draft], 1964 (Box 1)
    - "Epworth Notes" [correspondence and draft], 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - "Epworth Notes" [correspondence and draft], 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - "Epworth Notes" [correspondence and draft], 1965 (Box 1)
    - "Epworth Notes" [correspondence and draft], 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - "Conflict Can Be Constructive" [correspondence and drafts], 1965 (Box 1)
    - "A Family View of Vocation" [correspondence and drafts], 1966 (Box 1)
  - Confirmation study book, "A Search for Faith" (Box 1)
  - Biographical material and miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Printed sermons (Box 1)